Hello everyone, my name is Ian Barash, my project is the Multi-Signature Authentication
Web Proxy.
Today I'll be talking about how I spent a week researching cryptography and then threw
half of it away.
So my idea, it seemed perfect at the start.
I was going to use threshold signature cryptography, which requires several people to approve before
a sensitive action runs.
The same guarantees that protect crypto wallets.
So I went and I researched four of these schemes, Frost, Moosig2, GG20, and DKLS.
In these schemes, each approver holds a key and then their shares combine into one signature.
This means that no approver ever needs to trust the server with their secret.
This is cutting edge cryptography, it's very mathematically elegant and exactly what the
crypto world uses.
But it just didn't really fit with my project.
For one, every approver now becomes a key manager.
If you lose a key, the server can't help you.
And for approvers that are not technically savvy, that's not really what I wanted.
Second, the parties have to talk to each other.
They have to actually do the cryptography with themselves rather than with the server.
And when approvals can be hours apart, that didn't really seem very usable in my project
scope.
And three, the security still rests on the server.
There still needs to be code that's running on a server that the approvers will need to
trust.
And so even though you take away... if you compromise a key, it's basically the same
as compromising a password.
So that's what I decided to do.
Instead of doing the threshold cryptography, I did a credential-backed approval, where
approvers can sign in with a password and a one-time code.
And then each approval is cryptography tied to that login.
It's signed and it's tampered effort.
It's much simpler for people and it is strong where it counts.
So I wrote this up into an architecture design record, my first actually.
And really, I attribute this change to being so cheap because I did it on paper rather
than when I had a full code base that I would have to change.
So how does the flow actually work?
You can see it here.
The proxy requester will make HTTP requests to the proxies.
The proxy will store some artifacts and notify the approvers.
Once everything is approved, an executor will grab it, read the artifact, and then actually
publish it to the package repository.
And that is brought all the way back to the requester in an email link.
And the rest of the system is specified too.
So over the past two weeks, I, with some AI help, have written about 5,800 lines of code
over 32 commits, which are all specification, no actual application code yet.
And it really defines what the system is made of and how it'll talk together, every state
that a request can move through, the exact cryptography down to even the parameters that
I'll be using, a threat model, who uses it and why, that's all documented in the PRD,
as well as shared account access, self-service portals, and second factor logins.
Second factor access being the other use case that I am putting aside for now.
And then I ran a consistency audit to make sure that none of the documentation conflicted
with each other.
This really was to ensure that I was really going deep on the parts that actually mattered
rather than trying to describe a whole bunch of features and only half filled them out.
And so this is where I want your approval and your feedback.
So I built the flow that you saw in the previous slide for package publishing.
However, shared accounts, which is the second use case, login or user portals and second
factor logins, I'm really putting aside for only if time allows.
So I want to ask you, is this the first right place to build or have I over-scooped or under-scooped
DNDT?