Hi everyone, my name is Ian Barash and this is my practicum project, the Multi-Signature
Authentication Web Proxy.
Basic ideas, it's like MFA, but the factors are people.
I got the idea from Crypto Wallets, they've already solved this.
To be able to move funds from a critical account, you usually need to have multiple people sign
the request with their keys before the transaction is sent to the end user.
This means that no one person can forward millions of dollars on their own.
The group has to agree first.
And the security comes from the cooperation rather than trusting one individual with the
keys.
However, web logins still trust one person.
Things like a duo or if you self-host Othalia, they prove who you are, but none of them require
several distinct people to cooperate before granting access to a service.
The idea is a web proxy that grants access only when a quorum of approvers each provide
their secret key.
It'll sit in front of any web service and when a request is sent, it is caught, held,
and only released after enough people sign off on that request.
And ideally, no changes to the back-end application will be required.
Why does it matter?
Well, right now, one developer holds the keys to the kingdom.
Supply chain attacks on MPM and PiPI keep succeeding because compromising a single account
allows the attacker to ship malicious code to everyone downstream.
Without this, compromising one account turns into compromising the entire internet.
How's it going to work?
Well, like I mentioned, it'll intercept requests to an endpoint.
It'll then notify approvers on a defined access list.
It'll wait until a quorum is achieved, until enough people agree to that request, and it'll
be forwarded along to the endpoint.
Let's look at this use case concretely.
So publishing a package to PiPI.
For those of you who don't know, publishing a package is just HTTP.
So when a maintainer runs publish, instead of sending it to the public repository, they'll
be sending it to this web proxy.
It'll intercept and save the release instead of pushing it directly to the public.
The other maintainers are going to be notified that a package is awaiting release.
Approvals will be gathered until the quorum is reached, and then and only then will that
package be published to the public repository, stopping any one individual from publishing
it themselves.
Now it's still in the research phase.
This week I spent a lot of time refining and defining the problem, trying to find motivation
in real world use cases that are realistic and will help the security community.
I have found that package repository use case and have began researching some multi-signature
crypto primitives that will underlie the authentication scheme.
Next week I hope to choose an authentication scheme, write some of the high level architecture
and data flow specifications, and then specify some of the systems and how they'll work.
So three things I'd like your input on.
I'm still trying to figure out how to prevent bypassing the proxy.
I've thought if it's a web account that you're protecting, the web proxy will probably need
your credentials rather than allowing any user to have them.
But for other things, it's a little trickier.
Also the signature scheme that will underlie this.
Has anybody used any cryptographic multi-signature primitives or know of any that may be helpful
here?
I've done some research, but it's by no means conclusive.
And where else does this apply?
I've thought of that package publishing, but where else could requiring multiple people
to approve of a web request be useful in the real world?
That's all the time I have.
So thank you and I'll see you in a few weeks.